southernsun.com 2017-07-12

# Privacy Policy | Tsogo Sun Protects Your Privacy

Tsogo Sun is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Privacy Policy applies to The Tsogo Sun Web site and governs data collection and usage.

By using Tsogo Sun Website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

### Collection of Your Personal Information

Tsogo Sun collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. Tsogo Sun also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your postal or ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favourites.

Your privacy is very important to Tsogo Sun. To help protect your privacy, we adhere to the following guidelines. Tsogo Sun web sites will explicitly ask when they need information that personally identifies you or allows them to contact you ("Personal Information"). Generally this information is requested when making reservations, joining the Frequent Guest programme, registering for site usage, when requesting a particular service, when sending feedback or when entering a competition. Where possible, we will provide you with the means to make sure that your Personal Information is correct and current, alternatively you may request for your Personal Information to be updated. You also have the right to request that your personal information not be used for any other use except for the intended purpose of its collection.

Tsogo Sun will use your Personal Information to operate the sites, provide services, and to inform you of new features, services, and products. If we intend to use Personal Information for a Secondary Use, Tsogo Sun will provide you with the ability to decline this service.

Tsogo Sun web sites may disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) comply with applicable law or with legal process served on Southern Sun Hotels. or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Tsogo Sun, or this site, and (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of goods and services of Tsogo Sun, the site, or the public.

If at any time you believe that we have not adhered to these principles, please notify us and we will use all commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and correct the problem.

You should also be aware that information and data is automatically collected through the standard operation of the internet servers and through the use of "cookies." "Cookies" are small text files a web site can use to recognise repeat users, facilitate the user's on-going access to and use of the site and allow a site to track usage Behaviour and compile aggregate data that will allow content improvements and targeted advertising. Cookies are not programs that come onto your system and damage files. Generally, cookies work by assigning a unique number to you that has no meaning outside the assigning site. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to deny or accept the cookie feature; however, you should note that cookies may be necessary to provide you with certain features (e.g., customised delivery of information) available on the website.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by Tsogo Sun. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by Tsogo Sun for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of Tsogo Sun Web site.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through Tsogo Sun public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: Tsogo Sun does not read any of your private online communications.

Tsogo Sun encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites you choose to link to from Tsogo Sun so that you can understand how those Web sites collect, use and share your information. Tsogo Sun is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on Web sites outside of Tsogo Sun and The Tsogo Sun family of Web sites.

Tsogo Sun makes use of Google Analytics on its websites. Google Analytics is a service offered by Google that generates detailed statistics about a website's traffic and traffic sources and measures conversions and sales. Using the Ads Settings, visitors can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads. Visitors can also access to Google Analytics' currently available opt-outs. For further information please refer to Policy requirements for Display Advertising.

### Use of your Personal Information

Tsogo Sun collects and uses your personal information to operate Tsogo Sun Web site and deliver the services you have requested. Tsogo Sun also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from Tsogo Sun and its affiliates. Tsogo Sun may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

Tsogo Sun does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. Tsogo Sun may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, Tsogo Sun may share data with trusted partners to help us perform research and, historical and statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Tsogo Sun , and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information by way of confidentiality agreements. Should you wish that your personal information not be used in this manner, simply send ‘unsubscribe’ to [tsogogroup.webmaster@tsogosun.com](mailto:tsogogroup.webmaster@tsogosun.com.?subject=Corporate%20%20%7C%20Privacy%20Policy%20%20%7C%20Website%20enquiry).

Tsogo Sun does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

Tsogo Sun keeps track of the Web sites and pages our customers visit within Tsogo Sun , in order to determine what Tsogo Sun services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customised content and advertising within Tsogo Sun to customers whose behaviour indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

Tsogo Sun Web sites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Tsogo Sun or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Tsogo Sun ; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Tsogo Sun , or the public.

### Use of Cookies

Tsogo Sun Web site uses "cookies" to help you personalise your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalise Tsogo Sun pages, or register with Tsogo Sun site or services, a cookie helps Tsogo Sun to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same Tsogo Sun Web site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use Tsogo Sun features that you customised.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of Tsogo Sun services or Web sites you visit.

### Security of your Personal Information

Tsogo Sun take practical and reasonable steps to secure your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Tsogo Sun secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

### Changes to this Statement

Tsogo Sun will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. Tsogo Sun encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how Tsogo Sun is protecting your information.

### Contact Information

Tsogo Sun welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that Tsogo Sun has not adhered to this Statement, please contact Tsogo Sun via

Tel: +27 11 510-7700, Fax: +27 11 510-7277 or Email: [tsogogroup.webmaster@tsogosun.com](mailto:tsogogroup.webmaster@tsogosun.com.?subject=Corporate%20%20%7C%20Privacy%20Policy%20%20%7C%20Website%20enquiry). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
